"The Stranger I Met" Episode 7
'내가 만난 낯선 사람' 7회
(Wu Jindong)
(우진동)
(Kyung Gi Joo)
(주경기)
"A Stranger I Met"
"내가 만난 낯선 사람"
Did the blue hat show up?
파란 모자가 나타났나요?
(past story)
(지난 이야기)
there are more people
사람이 더 많아요
- Hersul - Brothers
- Hersul - 형제들
That night he fled the bridge
그날 밤 그는 다리에서 도망쳤다
The blue hat is Bahisu
파란색 모자는 바히수
Liu Fan believes
Liu Fan은 믿는다
The victim and I walked the same path.
피해자와 나는 같은 길을 걸었다.
One of the three current suspects
현재 용의자 3명 중 1명
a hidden blue hat
숨겨진 파란색 모자
Everything matches the location
모든 것이 위치와 일치합니다.
The person closest to the current defendant
현재 피고인과 가장 가까운 사람
your father
아버지
Bais
바이스
I'm talking about blue hat
파란 모자를 말하는 거야
The person who might have killed my mother
내 어머니를 죽였을지도 모르는 사람
have you seen?
봤어?
I think I can investigate
조사해볼 수 있을 것 같아요
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
(Section 7 - Overlapping paths)
(섹션 7 - 겹치는 경로)
Article (7)
제7조
Yes
예
I didn't even know it was wrong from the beginning
처음부터 잘못된 줄도 몰랐어
1987 Three Suspects
1987 세 명의 용의자
Produced by police who were unable to identify the arresting suspect
체포된 용의자를 특정하지 못한 경찰 이 제작
Find the real culprit from the list of suspects
용의자 목록에서 진짜 범인을 찾아보세요
( Suspect in Wu Jong-il serial murder case )
( 우정일 연쇄살인사건 용의자 )
that's wrong
그건 틀렸어요
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
I said I can bear it
견딜 수 있다고 했어
Excellent
훌륭한
Except these two
이 두 가지를 제외하고
this is not new
이건 새로운 게 아니야
Although I only found out five minutes ago
5분 전에야 알았지만
Although Sprite happened
스프라이트가 발생했지만
Where did you find this photo?
이 사진을 어디서 찾았나요?
This is my first time seeing
이건 처음 봐요
Looks like we need to investigate thoroughly
철저하게 조사해야 할 것 같습니다
Not very good at detective skills
탐정 능력이 별로 좋지 않음
No
아니요
It’s about Bayusu
바유스에 관한 것입니다
Among so many documents, there is no one
그 많은 서류 중에 한 사람도 없어
I don't think I'm a suspect
나는 용의자라고 생각하지 않는다
What kind of person have you become?
당신은 어떤 사람이 되었나요?
your great uncle
너의 큰 삼촌
Bayusu
바유스
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
Even though I thought I knew
안다고 생각했는데도
Until today I see you there
오늘까지 거기에서 만나요
(disco)
(디스코)
Too far away to call family
가족에게 전화하기엔 너무 멀다
People who are too close cannot be called strangers
너무 가까운 사람은 낯선 사람이라고 할 수 없다
but...
하지만...
That disappointingly familiar face
실망스러울 정도로 익숙한 그 얼굴
there is almost nothing there
거기엔 거의 아무것도 없어요
What are you doing now, uncle?
지금 뭐하세요, 삼촌?
Book
책
Didn't you tell me not to enter other people's rooms?
다른 사람 방에 들어가지 말라고 하지 않았나요?
Why are you doing this to me?
나한테 왜 이러는 걸까요?
- Almost let it go - Haha
- 거의 놔뒀어요 - 하하
- Nothing happened - Oops
- 아무 일도 일어나지 않았어 - 이런
(small door)
(작은 문)
Apologize
사과하다
excuse me
실례합니다
Don't shout
소리치지 마세요
we are family
우리는 가족
my father's family
내 아버지의 가족
Didn’t my mother and I have a place in it from the beginning ?
엄마와 나는 처음부터 그 자리에 있지 않았나요 ?
Do you think you don’t know enough?
당신이 충분히 모른다고 생각합니까?
That's why this isn't family to me, Dad
그래서 이건 나한테는 가족이 아니야, 아빠
Hey Yoon Young
안녕하세요 윤영님
hold on..
기다리다..
I do not know
모르겠어요
Do I really know that person?
내가 정말 그 사람을 아는 걸까?
What kind of nation has it become?
어떤 나라가 되었나요?
(Badminton eight events)
(배드민턴 8종목)
So you have to find out from here
그러니까 여기서부터 알아내야 해
I was shocked
나는 충격 받았다
- Bamboo - Come on
- 대나무 - 어서
From now on, I will ask three or four very simple questions
이제부터 아주 간단한 질문을 서너 가지 질문하겠습니다.
If there is a lie in the answer
답변에 거짓이 있는 경우
There is a parent-teacher meeting tomorrow morning
내일 아침에 학부모-교사 회의가 있습니다
it's not fair
그건 공평하지 않아
Parent-teacher conference teacher...
학부모 교사 회의 교사 ...
- Uncle totally ...
- 삼촌 완전 ...
Whose is that?
그거 누구꺼야?
Is this a hat?
이것은 모자인가요?
Not yet, the Night King is coming for him
아직은 나이트 킹이 그를 찾아오고 있어요
Why do other people's hats...
남의 모자는 왜...
Will they do it tomorrow?
내일 할 거예요?
I called my uncle at eight o'clock in the morning.
나는 아침 8시에 삼촌에게 전화를 걸었다.
Why my brother?
왜 내 동생이야?
I rented it for a while last night and watched it.
어젯밤에 잠시 빌려서 봤습니다.
last night..
어젯밤..
What is the real reason why he went to Wuzhen Inn Alley ?
그가 오진여관골목에 간 진짜 이유는 무엇일까 ?
Wait, I already said that
잠깐만, 내가 이미 말했잖아
every time i go for a walk
내가 산책하러 갈 때마다
If I'm wrong I'll ask more specifically
내 말이 틀렸다면 좀 더 구체적으로 물어볼게
last night..
어젯밤..
Until you change the direction of travel
여행 방향을 바꿀 때까지
Who asked you to take that path?
누가 당신에게 그 길을 가라고 하였나요?
The person who walked together but disappeared alone
함께 걷다가 혼자 사라진 사람
Just like walking out from in front of me
마치 내 앞에서 걸어나가는 것처럼
There is no point in lying
거짓말은 아무 소용이 없어요
Who is that?
그 사람은 누구입니까?
Please do not turn on the lights on the second floor
2층에는 불을 켜지 마세요.
Just confirm
그냥 확인하세요
WHO？
WHO?
Who asked you to do this?
누가 당신에게 이런 일을 하라고 하였나요?
Who is your own mouth?
당신의 입은 누구입니까?
mine..
내 거..
brother
형제
everything has been paid for
모든 비용은 지불되었습니다
Go to the second floor room where Lee Joo-young is alone at the match shop
성냥갑에서 이주영이 혼자 있는 2층 방 으로 이동
Do you want to know?
너 알고 싶니?
Last night, Lee Joo Young didn't even show up at Bom Bom Play House
어젯밤, 이주영은 봄봄 플레이하우스에도 나타나지 않았다
forced to do this
억지로 이런 짓을 하게 됐어
This means that Lee Joo Young was targeted from the beginning.
이주영이 처음부터 표적이 됐다는 뜻이다.
Not that, but here
그게 아니라 여기
The man ran away
그 남자는 도망갔다
Below is Lee Joo Young
아래는 이주영
Could it be that he was peeping and escaping at the same time?
혹시 그는 엿보는 동시에 도망치고 있었던 것은 아닐까 ?
owner of blue hat
파란 모자의 주인
The culprit is Bayusu
범인은 바유스
If you were in front of such power, you would feel dizzy
그런 힘 앞에 서면 어지러울 것 같아
If Ba Yusup is the real culprit
바유섭이 진짜 범인이라면
No need to wait, see you tomorrow night
기다리지 말고 내일 밤에 만나요
second victim
두 번째 희생자
Because you have to kill
죽여야 하기 때문에
Do you really have the confidence to face it yourself?
당신은 정말로 스스로 직면할 자신감이 있습니까?
I mean, there's no need to suppress this feeling.
내 말은, 이 감정을 억누를 필요가 없다는 것입니다.
It must be tiring and painful
힘들고 고통스러울 텐데
Because after all, we are family
결국 우리는 가족이니까
I'm disgusted, my heart is in chaos
역겨워 마음이 혼란 스러워
but before that
하지만 그 전에
The rest of my thoughts
내 생각의 나머지 부분
my mother
우리 엄마
And you..
당신은요..
There is only one thing that must be protected from despicable people
비열한 사람들로부터 지켜야 할 것이 딱 하나 있다
that's why
그렇기 때문에
Why not spread the word around the neighborhood?
동네에 소문을 퍼뜨리는 건 어떨까요?
About me and my mother
나와 내 어머니에 대해서
I'm just a little confused .
나는 조금 혼란스러워요 .
No one knows better than me
나보다 더 잘 아는 사람은 없어
Required Documents Missing Information
필수서류 누락정보
From now on I'll fill in everything you need
이제부터 네가 필요한 건 내가 다 채워줄게
from now on
지금부터
You never know what you'll find
당신은 당신이 무엇을 찾을지 결코 알 수 없습니다
Do you really have faith?
정말 믿음이 있나요?
Yes
예
(trash can)
(쓰레기통)
Who did what?
누가 무엇을 했나요?
If it were true I would know
그게 사실이라면 난 알았을 텐데
Won't run away at all
전혀 도망치지 않을 거야
because it can be protected
보호받을 수 있기 때문에
Are you there yet?
아직 거기 있나요?
Yes
예
Bring a change of clothes
갈아입을 옷을 가져오세요
What to do now?
이제 무엇을 해야 할까요?
i have to find out
난 알아내야 해
Start with who the second victim is.
두 번째 피해자가 누구인지부터 시작하세요.
who is it?
누구야?
Hello
안녕하세요
Contestant No. 2
참가자 2번
Ms. Gyeonggi
경기씨
Li Jing'e
리징에
please help
도와주세요
impossible
불가능한
Have you really not noticed something?
정말 뭔가 눈치채지 못하셨나요?
I found my absent aunt
부재중인 이모를 찾았어요
because of physical weakness
체력이 약해서
I only know that he died young due to illness
그가 병으로 인해 젊은 나이에 세상을 떠났다는 사실만 알고 있습니다.
Is there anything else that hasn’t been said yet?
아직 전해지지 않은 내용이 또 있나요?
Already displayed on the second floor
2층에도 이미 전시되어 있어요
this explains everything
이것이 모든 것을 설명한다
Do you have any plans this time?
이번에는 어떤 계획이라도 있나요?
Rented the house opposite
맞은편 집을 빌렸어요
Do you think this is a coincidence?
이것이 우연이라고 생각하시나요?
Everything starts from scratch...
모든 것은 처음부터 시작됩니다...
Judging from the results for the entire month
한 달 동안의 결과로 판단하면
Today will be the most difficult day
오늘은 가장 힘든 날이 될 것이다
Because the people we want to save are not ordinary people
우리가 구하고 싶은 사람들은 보통 사람들이 아니니까
(University Entrance Examination)
(대학입학시험)
(10,000 won)
(10,000원)
Find Dad's Emergency Fund
아빠의 비상금 찾기
I should have thought about it earlier
좀 더 일찍 생각 했어야 했는데
Yes, you can get it if you save a little more
응, 조금만 더 아껴쓰면 얻을 수 있어
Just a little more
조금만 더
Nickname Wu Zongri is crazy
별명 Wu Zongri는 미쳤다
The craziest crazy woman around
주변에서 가장 미친 미친 여자
Why are you doing what you are doing?
당신은 지금 하는 일을 왜 하고 있나요?
It is impossible to understand with normal thinking
정상적인 사고로는 이해가 불가능하다
that's why it's the front of the house
그래서 집 앞이야
Because I don't know what to do
왜냐면 난 무엇을 해야할지 모르거든요
At that time, the police found the route
당시 경찰은 경로를 찾아냈다.
It's hard to believe
믿기 ​​힘드네요
Missed too much
너무 많이 놓쳤어요
After what happened last night, I am even more sure
어젯밤에 일어난 일 이후로 더욱 확실해졌어
ah
아
Mother
어머니
Anyway, that's where those guys ended up
어쨌든, 그 사람들은 결국 거기서 끝났어
Bom Bom Ti House tonight at 9pm
봄봄티 하우스 오늘 밤 9시
Same as Lee Joo Young
이주영이랑 똑같네
I must have seen the defendant after I left there
나는 그곳을 떠난 후에 피고인을 만났나 봐요
Today is different
오늘은 다르다
Because we will be behind him
우리가 그 사람 뒤에 있을 테니까
This time for sure
이번엔 확실히
I will definitely do this
나는 반드시 이것을 할 것이다
our school
우리 학교
What
무엇
fever..
발열..
39 degrees
39도
Yeah, what should I do because I'm the only guardian
응, 보호자는 나뿐이니까 어떡하지?
Of course, if something goes wrong at school now, I have to go to the hospital as soon as possible
물론 지금은 학교에 무슨 일이라도 생기면 빨리 병원에 가야지
Do you know that hospital at the intersection?
교차로에 있는 그 병원을 아시나요?
You don’t have to worry about class at all
수업에 전혀 걱정하지 않으셔도 됩니다
Stay connected and take care of yourself
연결을 유지하고 자신을 돌보세요
Well, yes, yes
응, 응, 응
Mother
어머니
Not today
오늘 말고
You can get it if you go to the hospital
병원에 가시면 받으실 수 있어요
Oh, I'm on my way
아, 지금 가는 중이에요
So kids are better off?
그럼 아이들은 좀 나아졌나요?
Yes, I can be discharged
네, 퇴원할 수 있어요
I was asked to stay one more day
하루만 더 머물자고 했어요
Great, great
좋아 좋아
Take this opportunity to let the kids eat whatever they want.
이번 기회에 아이들이 먹고 싶은 것은 무엇이든 먹게 해주세요.
Let them see their father's face as they please
그들이 원하는 대로 아버지의 얼굴을 보게 해주세요
- Mr. Chairman, why are you doing this? - Take it.
- 의장님, 왜 이러시는 겁니까? - 받아요.
if i don't
내가하지 않으면
I didn’t dare to look at my son’s face for three or four days.
저는 3~4일 동안 감히 아들의 얼굴을 쳐다볼 엄두도 내지 못했습니다 .
curry
카레
It hangs you up so you can't walk
널 묶어서 걸을 수 없게 만드는 거야
Am I not?
나는 그렇지 않습니까?
Didn't do it on purpose
일부러 그러지 않았어
Excellent
훌륭한
cherry flavor
체리맛
Has Yin Yu returned to Korea now?
이제 유진이는 한국으로 돌아왔나요?
Well, the call came
자, 전화가 왔다
He will come back to see his father's face
그는 아버지의 얼굴을 보러 돌아올 것이다
It's been three years
3년이 지났어요
When slime appears before your eyes, think of it as gratitude
슬라임이 눈앞에 나타나면 감사하다고 생각하세요
They won't spend the rest of their lives in your arms like children.
그들은 아이들처럼 당신의 품에 안겨 남은 생애를 보내지 않을 것입니다.
Yes
예
Want to eat one?
하나 먹고 싶어?
Oh yes, thank you
아 네, 감사합니다
Really?
정말?
If I were a Korean wife, I would buy a fur coat
내가 한국인 아내라면 모피 코트를 살 것이다
Mother
어머니
Is this a child?
이 아이인가요?
Is a fur coat affordable for everyone?
모피 코트는 모든 사람에게 저렴한가요?
No compulsory purchase
강제 구매 없음
- I will buy - Madam
- 제가 사겠습니다 - 부인
If only my mother were a Korean lady
우리 엄마가 한국여자였더라면
Don't cheat and try to stop drinking
속이지 말고 술을 끊으려고 노력 하라
Miss Korea
미스코리아
- I was rude to my sister. - It's okay.
- 언니한테 무례하게 굴었어요 - 괜찮아요
What about everything that happened to me?
나에게 일어난 모든 일은 어떻게 되나요?
In other words, I definitely have potential
즉, 나는 확실히 잠재력을 갖고 있다.
Talking about 500,000 won again makes me sick
또 50만원 얘기하면 마음이 아프다
It's not like you meet someone you don't know
모르는 사람을 만나는 것도 아니고
My mother said she didn't know
어머니는 모른다고 하셨다
But can you support me a little bit?
하지만 조금만 응원해 주실 수 있나요?
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
not a penny
한 푼도 아니야
Can't we hire a math teacher?
수학 선생님을 고용할 수는 없나요?
I can't catch up now
지금은 따라잡을 수 없어
Now the college entrance examination is approaching
이제 대학입시가 코앞으로 다가왔습니다
If you add a little more to my savings...
내 저축에 조금 더 보탬이 된다면...
It doesn't matter
그것은 중요하지 않습니다
he is
그는
What should I do when I don't recognize this shadow?
이 그림자를 인식하지 못할 경우 어떻게 해야 합니까?
Sun E
썬E
If I had extra money, I would definitely hire a teacher
돈이 더 있다면 반드시 선생님을 고용하겠습니다.
father is late
아버지가 늦었어
Goodbye my daughter
안녕 내 딸
Of course I have to buy some mother and son books
물론 엄마와 아들 책도 사야지
If that's not enough, say it again
부족하면 다시 말씀해주세요
don't tell your sisters
언니들한테는 말하지 마
want to go
가고 싶다
Neither noticed nor missed
눈치채지도 놓치지도 않았어
I said I work in a hair salon
내가 미용실에서 일한다고 했어
So are you going to work?
그럼 일하러 가시나요?
I lost my job without notice over something as simple as that.
나는 그런 단순한 일로 예고도 없이 직장을 잃었습니다 .
There is no record of what he did during this period
이 기간 동안 그가 무엇을 했는지에 대한 기록은 없습니다.
You will know if you follow me in the future
앞으로 나를 따라오면 알게 될 거야
Quiet
조용한
Do you have
당신은 가지고 있습니까?
Hey Shan'e, did you do this on purpose?
안녕하세요 Shan'e, 일부러 이러셨나요?
What am I doing?
나는 무엇을하고 있는가?
Just because you think my dreams are interesting
내 꿈이 재미있다고 생각하니까
Interrupting and talking about you like this
끼어들고 이렇게 네 얘기를 하다가
Don't spend your money where there is no such hope
그런 희망이 없는 곳에 돈을 쓰지 마세요
Use it on my smart girl, don't you think?
내 똑똑한 여자한테 써먹을 생각은 아니지?
I'm sorry to bother you
당신을 귀찮게해서 미안 해요
I really don’t know because I didn’t listen to my sister
언니 말을 안 들어봐서 잘 모르겠어요.
Don't listen...
듣지 마세요 ...
Now I'm going to ignore this ratio
이제 이 비율을 무시하겠습니다.
No, that doesn't mean
아니요, 그런 뜻은 아닙니다
Hey, you're good at it, remember?
이봐, 너 잘하는구나, 기억나?
that clip
그 클립
that's what i'm worried about
그게 내가 걱정하는 거야
My dad only bought you one
아빠가 하나만 사줬어
Why is the whole school Level 1?
왜 학교 전체가 1등급인가요?
So I was loved
그래서 나는 사랑받았어요
Until then, you know what?
그때까지는 그거 알아요?
Do you think my father doesn’t accept you as a teacher because he really has no money?
우리 아버지가 정말 돈이 없어서 당신을 선생님으로 받아들이지 않을 것 같나요 ?
What's that word?
그 단어는 무엇입니까?
you..
너..
My father had no intention of sending me to college
아버지는 나를 대학에 보낼 생각이 전혀 없었습니다.
How did my sister know?
언니는 어떻게 알았지?
You're the only one who doesn't know
모르는 사람은 너뿐이야
What was the father's wish from the beginning?
처음부터 아버지의 소원은 무엇이었나요?
you and me
너와 나
Marry into a good family early
좋은 집에 일찍 결혼해라
I want not to get a drop of water on my hands
손에 물 한방울도 묻히지 않으려면
After requesting ABO study
ABO 스터디 신청 후
I want to find a good job and stay
좋은 일자리를 찾아서 계속 머물고 싶어요
these two wishes
이 두 가지 소원
but you are not like that
하지만 당신은 그렇지 않아요
That's it
그게 다야
Will my sister do the same?
내 여동생도 그렇게 해줄까?
- What - just like my father.
- 뭐 - 우리 아버지랑 똑같아.
I'm not like that
나는 그렇지 않다
You can write without taking classes
수업을 듣지 않고도 글을 쓸 수 있다
If my sister needs to do this too
내 여동생도 이 일을 해야 한다면
use this or fill it out
이것을 사용하거나 작성하세요
I never thought this was funny
난 이게 재미있다고 생각해본 적이 없어
Are you reading this to be smart or what?
똑똑해지려고 이 글을 읽는 건가요?
I ignored it until the end
끝까지 무시했어요
(10,000 won)
(10,000원)
ha
하아
I am angry
나 화나
I can go alone
혼자 갈 수 있어요
It is not
그렇지 않다
Now I wish my mom would follow this direction
이제 엄마가 이 길을 따라갔으면 좋겠다
(pay phone)
(공중전화)
This is the first time I resent my grandfather
할아버지를 원망한 건 이번이 처음이다
This is my mother's lifelong wish
이게 우리 엄마의 평생 소원이에요
In the end I failed to go to college
결국 나는 대학에 가지 못했다.
This was not unusual at the time
당시엔 이런 일이 흔하지 않았어
Caste pain is not common
카스트 통증 은 흔하지 않습니다
It means I don’t know enough
내가 잘 모른다는 뜻이다
How will you feel about blocking your daughter's choice later?
나중에 딸의 선택을 막는 것에 대해 어떻게 생각하시나요?
What is he doing?
그는 무엇을 하고 있나요?
no matter what you do
당신이 뭘 하든지
We just wait for the defendant to come out
피고인이 나오길 기다리면 됩니다
No more changes can be made
더 이상 변경할 수 없습니다.
kakao
카카오
Hello
안녕하세요
How are you, beautiful?
잘 지내요, 아름다워요?
finally ready
드디어 준비됐어
So what are they?
그럼 그들은 무엇입니까?
What should happen?
무슨 일이 일어나야 할까요?
Friends who are preparing for the Miss Korea competition with you
미스코리아 대회를 함께 준비하고 있는 친구들
He will first conduct South Chora
그는 먼저 사우스 코라(South Chora)를 지휘할 것이다.
He is the greatest ancient
그는 가장 위대한 고대인이다
Gyeongbuk Region 3rd place
경북지역 3위
I gave 500,000 to make the second one
두 번째 것을 만들기 위해 500,000을 기부했습니다
Oh, sorry for the second time
아, 두 번째로 미안해요
Now
지금
our handsome guy
우리 잘생긴 남자
Where will Gyeonggi Province take it?
경기도는 어디로 가져갈까?
second
두번째
Second or first?
두 번째인가요, 첫 번째인가요?
Enter now
지금 입장하세요
hurry up
서둘러요
let's go
갑시다
(Wanted for fraud)
(사기 수배)
up
위로
What are you doing I do not have time. hurry up
뭐하세요 내가 시간이 없어. 서둘러요
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
As expected, today is the day I was deceived.
역시 오늘은 내가 속은 날이다.
Am I being scammed or something?
내가 사기를 당하고 있는 걸까?
about half a million
약 50만
They will make me Miss Korea
날 그리워하게 만들거야
- Come on - From the day I first came here
- 어서 - 내가 여기 처음 왔을 때부터
they improvise
그들은 즉흥적으로
Even if you get money out of it
돈을 벌어도
Because I spent all my money on booze and cash
술과 현금에 돈을 다 썼으니까
No money to cheat
속일 돈도 없어
That money is my mother's money
그 돈은 우리 엄마 돈이야
I can not afford it
감당할 수 없어
Why can't you afford it?
왜 그럴 여유가 없나요?
500,000 tuition fees?
등록금 500,000?
Did you grow up in a wealthy family or were you an only child?
부유한 가정에서 자랐나요, 아니면 외동딸이었나요?
I don't know because I don't live as a daughter
딸로 살지 않아서 모르겠어요
That's why I can be so calm
그래서 난 이렇게 침착할 수 있어
what are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
If you give it back, this won't happen
돌려주면 이런 일은 일어나지 않을 거에요
Mom, what happened suddenly?
엄마, 갑자기 무슨 일이에요?
We must go to Seoul together as soon as possible
하루빨리 함께 서울로 가야 해
No matter what happens
무슨 일이 있어도
There is a child in our family. He is stupid but very smart.
우리 집에 아이가 있는데, 그 아이는 멍청하지만 아주 똑똑해요.
Because I worry about him sometimes
가끔 그 사람이 걱정되니까
Next year, he will be admitted
내년에 입학한다
I will participate in the competition next year
나는 내년에 대회에 참가할 것이다
what are you saying?
당신이 무슨 말을하는거야?
- Haha- No way
- 하하- 말도 안돼
What are you doing hurry up
뭐하세요 서둘러요
- Ah - this guy
- 아 - 이 사람
hehe
헤헤
strength
힘
really quiet
정말 조용하다
hehe
헤헤
- Ha - Wait a minute.
- 하 - 잠깐만요.
- Call Kyung Yi first - Yeah.. Daw Lay Ray
- 경이에게 먼저 전화해 ​​- 응.. 도레이 레이
- Mom - Where have you been?
- 엄마 - 어디 갔었어?
Mom, try to let go
엄마, 놓아 보세요
The bastard who pays back the money
돈 갚는 새끼
Hey, this girl...
야, 이 여자...
hehe
헤헤
Mother
어머니
- Ha - Really
- 하 - 정말요
- Sun Lane - Hen
- 선 레인 - 편
how do you know?
어떻게 알아?
I don't ask because I think it would be difficult
어려울 것 같아서 묻지 않아요
I really want to know
나는 정말로 알고 싶다
How recently have you moved to school ?
최근에 학교로 이사하셨나요 ?
let's be friends
우리 친구 하자
only when we feel comfortable with each other
서로 편할 때만
Yes or no
예 혹은 아니오
you are right
당신 말이 맞아요
the person I like
내가 좋아하는 사람
love at first sight..
첫눈에 반하다..
But you know the result
하지만 결과는 아시죠?
Even when he opened up, he was rejected
열어도 거절당함
someone is hanging out
누군가 놀고 있어요
He doesn't accept my feelings
그 사람은 내 감정을 받아들이지 않아요
This guy is honest
이 사람은 솔직해요
thanks for letting me know
알려 줘서 고마워
What?
무엇?
Ah, why?
아, 왜요?
ha
하아
- Should I pay for anything?
- 비용을 지불해야 하나요 ?
- Do I have to pay? - What?
- 돈을 내야 하나요? - 뭐라고요?
What will you give?
무엇을 줄 것인가?
Can I get you a sundae?
아이스크림 하나 드릴까요?
What
무엇
just kidding
농담이야
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
Are you still affected?
아직도 영향을 받고 있나요?
Why now, why start now?
왜 지금, 왜 지금 시작하는가?
This is not a place to meet
이곳은 만날 수 있는 곳이 아니다
If you knew it was me who was chasing you that night
그날 밤 널 쫓던 게 나라는 걸 알았더라면
Ba Yusup is not in this situation, except...
바유섭은 이런 상황이 아닌데...
Because of me?
나 때문에?
Because of Li Jing'e?
이징어 때문에?
So this is something that has or has not happened before
그래서 이것은 이전에 일어났거나 일어나지 않은 일 입니다.
Is this a new problem?
이것이 새로운 문제인가요?
We are fine, how are you?
우리는 괜찮아요, 잘 지내요?
Thanks
감사해요
I don't think it's easy to get into
들어가기가 쉽지 않은 것 같아요
I thought I was passing by by accident and I should do something to help.
우연히 지나가다가 뭔가 도와줘야겠다는 생각이 들었어요.
Don't you think so?
그렇게 생각하지 않나요?
Yes
예
I did something big
내가 뭔가 큰 일을 했어
Everyone, wait here for a moment
다들 여기서 잠시만 기다려주세요
I just went to the police station to report
방금 경찰서에 신고하러 갔어요
How did this happen?
어떻게 이런일이 일어 났습니까?
Scammers also pass by here...
여기도 사기꾼들이 지나다니는데...
catch them all
다 잡아라
There is also the possibility of human trafficking
인신매매 가능성도 있다
i will understand
나는 이해할 것이다
I think it's a detective
탐정인 것 같아요
- Let's go. - Of course.
- 가자 - 물론이지
- Not a detective? - police?
- 탐정이 아니신가요? - 경찰?
- Police - Can you help us?
- 경찰 - 도와주실 수 있나요?
- They took our money - Yeah.
- 그 사람들이 우리 돈을 가져갔어 - 네.
- Can you take me home ?
- 저를 집에 데려다 주실 수 있나요 ?
- Please - No
- 제발 - 아니오
- Mom will kill me. - Help me get home.
- 엄마가 날 죽일 ​​거예요 - 집에 갈 수 있게 도와주세요
- Please help me
- 도와주세요
- Mom will be angry - What will they do?
- 엄마가 화를 내실 거예요. - 그 분들은 어떻게 하실 거예요?
- Call my mom - please
- 엄마한테 전화해 - 제발
- Mom - I have to go home.
- 엄마 - 집에 가야 해요.
- If you don't call, you'll die - Ha
- 전화 안 하면 죽는다 - 하하
Did they really disappear together?
정말 함께 사라진 걸까?
Last night we...
어젯밤에 우리는...
Remember how I told you what to do if you had to?
해야 할 경우 어떻게 해야 하는지 제가 어떻게 말했는지 기억하시나요 ?
yes, I remember
네 기억합니다
so be careful
그러니 조심해
if it is true
그것이 사실이라면
Although there is absolutely no such thing
전혀 그런건 없는데도
if anything changes
뭔가 변화가 있다면
if you miss the victim
피해자를 그리워한다면
Well
잘
Yes
예
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
Unusual, stop immediately
이상해, 당장 그만둬
come over
이리와
did you sleep well?
잘 잤어요?
As far as I know, no
내가 아는 한, 아니오
Does it matter?
그게 그렇게 중요한 건가?
It is said that the most abundant sad drama in the world is
세상에서 가장 풍부한 슬픈 드라마는 바로
Why are you doing so much?
왜 그렇게 많은 일을 하고 있나요?
Everyone is a stranger to you, right?
당신에게는 모두가 낯설죠?
If you can save everyone, you can't survive
모두를 구할 수 있다면 살아남을 수 없다
Just find the culprit
그냥 범인을 찾아보세요
Easier and cheaper way
더 쉽고 저렴한 방법
I think no matter how many there are
제 생각엔 아무리 많아도
The ground is cold
땅이 차갑다
(3 months in 2022)
(2022년에는 3개월)
When I first learned of my death and went looking for it
처음 나의 죽음을 알고 찾으러 갔을 때
All conditions are met
모든 조건이 충족됨
three months
삼 개월
The murder happened two months ago
살인은 두 달 전에 일어났어요
Because the destination that can be decided is only one year
정할 수 있는 목적지는 단 1년이니까
If you want to meet the defendant there
그곳에서 피고인을 만나고 싶다면
There is nothing to do but wait
할 일이 없으니 기다려라
Until he comes back a month later
한 달 뒤에 돌아올 때까지
A whole ten months
총 10개월
No matter what, people die once in a while
무슨 일이 있어도 사람은 한 번씩 죽는다.
This is a very bad ending
이거 너무 안좋은 결말이네
There at that time
그 당시에는
By chance he found a garbage man
우연히 그는 쓰레기꾼을 발견했습니다
Because everything ended in an instant
모든 게 한 순간에 끝났 으니까
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
The weather is cold
날씨가 추워
lie down like abandoned
버려진 것처럼 누워
But such a person
그런데 그런 사람이
After realizing there is more elsewhere
다른 곳에 더 많은 것이 있다는 것을 깨달은 후에
Then I got scared
그러다 겁이 났어요
Because I can't stop it because I know
알기 때문에 멈출 수가 없으니까
know means change
안다는 것은 변화를 의미한다
That is..
그건..
Because that's a pretty heavy expectation
꽤 큰 기대를 걸고 있는 거니까
Responsible for where Bayusu can be found
바유스를 찾을 수 있는 곳을 담당합니다
how about you?
당신은 어떤가요?
I 'll go where the murders actually happened
살인이 실제로 일어난 곳으로 갈 게요
(Mysterious murder case, the body was found with its hands and neck tied)
(미스테리한 살인사건, 양손과 목이 묶인 채 발견된 시체)
(Another female body was found, a 20-year-old female was killed)
(또 다른 여성 시신 발견, 20대 여성 사망)
(Sun and Moon Record Store)
(해와 달 레코드 가게)
what does that mean?
그게 무슨 뜻이야?
do you know?
당신은 알고 있나요?
I just wish I hadn't found it
내가 그걸 찾지 못했더라면 좋았을 텐데
(20-year-old college student was found murdered)
(20대 대학생이 살해된 채 발견됐다)
( The body of a school teacher was found on the bank of a river in a quiet village )
( 한적한 마을의 강둑에서 학교 선생님의 시신이 발견되었습니다. )
That is..
그건..
This must mean it's too late
이건 너무 늦었다는 뜻이겠지
(Wuzhuang Grocery Store)
(우좡 식료품점)
Think it's too late?
너무 늦었다고 생각하시나요?
I haven't found any clues yet
아직 단서를 찾지 못했어요
not enough
부족한
So where exactly are you doing?
그럼 정확히 어디서 뭐하고 계시나요?
all roads and roads
모든 도로와 도로
Yes
예
I don't know if I'm doing something
내가 뭔가를 하고 있는지 모르겠어
If nothing really happened
정말 아무 일도 일어나지 않았다면
Could it be doing something somewhere?
어딘가에서 뭔가 하고 있는 게 아닐까?
But we can get a good end result
하지만 우리는 좋은 결과를 얻을 수 있습니다
Don't you think I'm just looking for a place like this?
내가 이런 곳을 찾고 있는 것 같지 않니?
Just enough place to kill someone
누군가를 죽일 만큼 충분한 장소
If Bayusu and I are together, I'm sure...
바유스와 내가 함께라면 분명...
No
아니요
If so, the field would be very broad
그렇다면 그 분야는 매우 광범위할 것이다.
what time is it now?
지금 몇 시야?
9 hours and 10 minutes
9시간 10분
Ordinary shop
일반 가게
This was the last location recorded by police
경찰이 마지막으로 기록한 장소다.
things have changed
여러가지가 바뀌었다
- No reason to go there now.. - No reason not to go there.
- 이제 안 갈 이유가 없어요.. - 안 갈 이유가 없어요.
I know I'm afraid of change
나도 변화를 두려워한다는 걸 알아
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
No matter what you do, the result is the same.
무엇을 하든 결과는 같습니다.
Such problems often exist
이런 문제가 종종 존재합니다
- That's what time is
- 그게 바로 시간이에요
I don't even know this is time, this is love
때가 된지도 모르겠어 이게 사랑이야
It's a feeling hidden like fog
안개처럼 가려진 느낌이야
This is love that shines like the morning star
샛별처럼 빛나는 사랑이군요
Yesterday too
어제도
- It was all yesterday
- 다 어제였어
Today too
오늘도
- Today - Today all
- 오늘 - 오늘 모두
Tomorrow too
내일도
- I can't stand the entrance being closed - all the time
- 입구가 항상 닫혀 있는 걸 참을 수 없어요 - 항상
- That's what I want to hear - Please sit down quickly
- 그게 듣고 싶어요 - 빨리 앉으세요
- Let's sing I like you together - I like you
- 같이 노래하자 - 좋아해요 - 좋아해요
bamboo
대나무
- you like me
- 당신은 나를 좋아해요
I want to say this every day
매일 이 말을 하고 싶어
heart-warming moments
마음이 따뜻해지는 순간들
If you don't understand, let's sit down
이해가 안되면 앉자
This is the love we can share with each other
이것이 우리가 서로 나눌 수 있는 사랑이다
You like me and I like you too
당신도 나를 좋아하고 나도 당신을 좋아해요
Is Gominsu also on the suspect list?
고민수도 피의자 명단에 있나요?
He was imprisoned as a defendant for more than thirty years
그는 피고인으로 30년 넘게 투옥되었다.
Although he ultimately refused
결국 거절했지만
Is that Ge Minsu?
게민수야?
Why and how?
왜 그리고 어떻게?
Although there were three or four witnesses
증인이 서너 명 있었는데도
The main decision is the witness
주된 결정은 증인이다
He said he witnessed the murder
살인을 목격했다고 하더군요
My sister, Wu Xu
내 여동생, 우쑤(Wu Xu)
The Wuguang I know?
내가 아는 우광?
One of the two must be lying
둘 중 하나는 거짓말을 하고 있는 게 틀림없어
At least tonight is for sure
적어도 오늘 밤은 확실해
Whose words are true?
누구의 말이 사실인가요?
- Sing another song - Okay
- 다른 노래 불러보기 - 알았어
they are breaking up
그들은 헤어지고 있어요
( Suspect in Wu Jong-il serial murder case )
( 우정일 연쇄살인사건 용의자 )
I will go find my mother
나는 어머니를 찾으러 갈 것이다
Now suddenly?
이제 갑자기?
Go on tell me who's lying
어서 누가 거짓말을 하는지 말해봐
Li Jing'e
리징에
our little aunt
우리 작은 이모
I must
나는 해야 한다
Now we enter the second round
이제 2라운드에 들어갑니다
- Let's go.
- 가자
GR8
GR8
- always the best - thank you
- 항상 최고입니다 - 감사합니다
Where are they going?
그들은 어디로 가는 걸까요?
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
This guy..
이 남자..
let's go
갑시다
ah
아
- I have to go
- 가야 해
- I'm leaving - Tarta
- 나는 떠난다 - 타르타
- Will you come back? - See you tomorrow
- 돌아올 거예요? - 내일 봐요
- Gone - Tata
- 사라졌다 - 타타
strength
힘
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
How far do you want to go?
얼마나 멀리 가고 싶나요?
Because I have something to say
할 말이 있으니까
(hostel)
(호스텔)
Where did Li Zhuying go in the end?
Li Zhuying은 결국 어디로 갔습니까?
What did he do?
그가 무슨 짓을 한거야?
(hotel entrance)
(호텔 입구)
What's your job?
당신의 직업은 무엇입니까?
if you have something to say
할 말이 있다면
if they break up
만약 그들이 헤어지면
I know, I will do what you want
알아요, 당신이 원하는 대로 할게요
So you want to surrender to me too
그러니까 너도 나한테 항복하려는 거야?
Hey yubum
안녕 유붐
I have to break up without doing anything.
아무것도 하지 못한 채 헤어져야 해요.
I'm too good to be immune
면역력이 너무 좋은데
In the meantime I give you the time
그 사이에 나는 너에게 시간을 주겠다.
Yes or no
예 혹은 아니오
release
풀어 주다
save me, save me
구해줘, 구해줘
hehe
헤헤
Let's go somewhere and have another drink
어디 가서 한잔 더 마시자
They said they wanted to sit at the same table
같은 테이블에 앉고 싶다고 하더군요
What do your friends think of me?
친구들은 나를 어떻게 생각하나요?
Because other friends just sit there for a while
다른 친구들은 잠시 거기 앉아있으니까
I don't deal with garbage like you
난 너 같은 쓰레기는 안 상대해
He speaks beautifully
그는 말을 아름답게 한다
If you don't want to hear more beautiful words, just leave
더 아름다운 말을 듣고 싶지 않다면 그냥 떠나세요
Even if not, I'm still very angry today
그렇지 않더라도 오늘도 너무 화가 나네요
I want to take it easy today
오늘은 좀 쉬고 싶은데
You shoot first
먼저 쏘세요
Son, are you okay?
아들아, 괜찮아?
Hey, boss, are you hurt somewhere?
저기, 보스, 어디 다치셨나요?
This guy
이 남자
you are no longer friends
당신은 더 이상 친구가 아닙니다
Let's go, sun
가자, 태양아
try to die
죽으려고 노력하다
ha
하아
I think I'm dead, what should I do?
죽은 것 같은데 어떻게 해야 하나요?
How to do it?
어떻게 하나요?
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
hold on
기다리다
I think I have a broken bone
내 생각엔 뼈가 부러진 것 같아
(Li Jing'e, Li Zhouying)
(리징어, 리저우잉)
(Cause of death - cranial nerve compression asphyxia)
(사망원인 - 뇌신경 압박 질식)
a bone is broken
뼈가 부러졌다
Currently I am unable to do any form of bundling
현재 어떤 형태의 번들링도 할 수 없습니다.
please call my mom
엄마한테 전화해 주세요
Mother
어머니
Let's go, Li Jing'e
가자, 리징에
Why did it really disappear?
진짜 왜 없어졌지?
- Wait until the police come - But
- 경찰이 올 때까지 기다리세요 - 하지만
Didn't you hear?
못 들었어?
Can it really be left like this?
정말 이대로 놔둬도 되는 걸까?
drinking
음주
If something like this happens...
이런 일이 생기면...
It doesn't matter
그것은 중요하지 않습니다
Because I'm the only witness
내가 유일한 증인이니까
I just saw you tweet
방금 당신의 트윗을 봤어요
eyewitness?
목격자?
That's why I'm currently cautious
그래서 요즘 조심스러워요
He rarely drinks and comes home early
술도 거의 안 마시고 집에 일찍 온다.
If he is caught, he will have to pay a lot of money
잡히면 돈 많이 내야 할 듯
do you know?
당신은 알고 있나요?
Yes
예
I rarely drink
나는 거의 마시지 않는다
if you go home early
집에 일찍 가면
How can I see my parents' faces clearly?
어떻게 하면 부모님의 얼굴을 또렷하게 볼 수 있나요?
How can I look at my sister's face because I feel ashamed
부끄러워서 어떻게 언니 얼굴을 볼 수 있겠어요?
Well
잘
I'm 22 and I'm sure there's nothing I can do
나는 22살이고 내가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없다고 확신한다
disappointing
실망스러운
Are you a liar now?
지금 당신은 거짓말쟁이인가요?
I no longer have the ability to live
더 이상 살아갈 능력이 없어
I'm exhausted
난 지쳤어
I really can't stand it anymore
정말 더는 못 참겠어
Miss Korea...
미스코리아...
Not really yet
아직은 아니다
But according to what I observed at the same time
하지만 동시에 관찰한 바에 따르면
Woo Jae Ri Geun Sun’s statement is roughly correct
우재리근선님 말씀이 대략 맞네요
It's not bad to always dance in the club
클럽에서 맨날 춤추는 것도 나쁘지 않아
It's also great at making friends laugh
친구를 웃게 만드는 데에도 좋습니다
dress up
차려 입다
I have an eye for fashion
나는 패션에 눈이 있다
Not Miss Korea, but many people on TV
미스코리아는 아니지만 TV에 나오는 많은 사람들
If you know exactly what you want to do, you're around 22 years old
자신이 하고 싶은 일이 무엇인지 정확히 안다면 22세 정도입니다.
you can be young
당신은 젊을 수 있습니다
for real..
진짜로..
Do you think so?
그렇게 생각?
this is not a lie
이건 거짓말이 아니야
How can someone who has been robbed of all their money be defrauded again?
전 재산을 빼앗긴 사람이 어떻게 다시 사기를 당할 수 있습니까?
that money
그 돈
This really doesn't allow this poor little boy to pay his tuition.
이것은 정말로 이 불쌍한 어린 소년이 수업료를 지불하는 것을 허용하지 않습니다 .
ha
하아
You didn't lie, did you?
당신은 거짓말을 하지 않았죠?
try to drink with everything
뭐든지 다 마셔보려고 해
gentlemen
신사
Rob
롭
Well
잘
I took it back when I took it back unknowingly before.
예전에 나도 모르게 다시 가져갔을 때 다시 가져갔다 .
my God
맙소사
Mother
어머니
so so..
그저 그래..
Can I give it to grandma?
할머니한테 드릴까요?
What
무엇
I can't go back
돌아갈 수 없어
Hey, Lee Seung Yi
안녕하세요 이승이님
- Do you know what happened today because of this - sister?
- 이 일 때문에 오늘 무슨 일이 일어났는지 아세요 - 언니?
- Sister - Sorry, son E
- 언니 - 미안해, 아들 E
I'm sorry for what I just said
방금 말한 것 때문에 미안해요
- I'm sorry - Sister
- 미안해요 - 언니
i'm angry with you
난 너에게 화났어
(Lee Hyoman)
(이효만)
thank you for everything you did today
오늘 당신이 한 모든 일에 감사드립니다
Did not see the defendant
피고인을 보지 못함
I think I'm coming out of the fog a little now
이제 조금 안개 속에서 나올 것 같아요
I don't know what went wrong again
또 무슨 일이 일어났는지 모르겠어
Now there's only one chance left
이제 기회는 단 한 번 남았습니다
But it's clear
하지만 분명해
I am very satisfied with the scenery today
오늘 풍경이 너무 만족스러워요
Hello
안녕하세요
Who are you?
누구세요?
teacher
선생님
i believe in euben
난 유벤을 믿어
died
사망 한
he is dead sir
그는 죽었습니다 선생님
it finally happened
드디어 그런 일이 일어났어요
"A Stranger I Met"
"내가 만난 낯선 사람"
How did it happen?
어떻게이 일이 일어 났어요?
i have to explain
설명해야 해
What you see is what you do
당신이 보는 것이 당신이 하는 일이다
Explain everything from start to finish
처음부터 끝까지 다 설명해주세요
You didn't go out, did you?
너 밖에 안 나갔지, 그렇지?
Time and place have changed, but death remains the same
시간과 장소는 변했지만 죽음은 그대로다
I've never died in a place like this
난 이런 곳에서 죽은 적이 없어
It all comes full circle and this is where we end up
모든 것이 원을 그리며 우리는 여기서 끝난다
This village is not human, why do you want to come here to die?
이 마을은 사람도 아닌데 왜 여기 와서 죽으려고 합니까?
Why is it so stable?
왜 이렇게 안정적일까요?
Try to relax your face
얼굴의 긴장을 풀어보세요
this is very obvious
이건 아주 명백해
"A Stranger I Met"
"내가 만난 낯선 사람"